Guide to the George Charles Poppensiek papers, 1942-2013.
Poppensiek, George Charles papers
- Series I. General Files
  - History of Veterinary Medicine; Centennial Celebration, College of Veterinary Medicine., n.d. (Box 16, Folder 16)
  - Commencement Booklets: University o Pennsylvania, One Hundred and Eighty-Sixth Commencement for the Conferring of Degrees, 2 June 1942; Cornell University, Eighty-fourth Annual Commencement, 9 June 1952, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 17)
  - Speeches, Certificates, News clippings, Correspondence, 1950-1965 (Box 16, Folder 18)
  - Speeches, Certificates, Photographs, News clippings, Correspondence, 1936-2000 (Box 16, Folder 19)
  - George C. Poppensiek Visiting Professorship in International Veterinary Medicine, 1989-2000 (Box 16, Folder 20)
  - Photographs: Retired Faculty Members, College of Veterinary Medicine (Box 16, Folder 21)
  - College of Veterinary Medicine Class Photographs, 1962-1990 (Box 16, Folder 22)
  - Beyond Traditional Boundaries: Veterinary medicine at Cornell in the Twenty First Century, October 2000 (Box 16, Folder 23)
  - James LeGrande Shupe, Dedication to George C. Poppensiek, 1966-2006 (Box 16, Folder 24)
    Also items relating to articles on Flourides, "The Pathology of Chronic Bovine Flourisis, A Review", Flourides: Effects on Vegetation, Animals and Humans
  - Interview with Stephanie A. Specchio, Communications manager, College of Veterinary Medicine, Summer 2011 (Box 16, Folder 25)
  - Some writings and reprints, most by Poppensiek, Various (Box 16, Folder 26)
    Includes: "Hungry Minds and the Empty Bowl of Grammar and Rhetoric", "Emphasis on Concepts in the Teaching of Veterinary Microbiology", "Language in Education: The Neglected Responsibility of Contemporary American Society", "Welcome to Buffalo", "Animal Diseases Transmissible to Man", Veranus Alba Moore obituary from Journal of Bacteriology, July 1931.
  - Biographical and career information, Various (Box 16, Folder 27)
    Includes: Biography, Marriage advice project interview form, requirements for the George C. Poppensiek visting professorship, press release for winning the Centennial Medal. Also a photo at his desk at the Cornell Vet School and a photo of the 1940 National Alpha Psi fraternity Convention March 22-23, 1940, in Auburn, Alabama
- Series II. Correspondence
  - A, March 1974 - October 1981 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Alvarez, Dr. Emiliano, December 1978 - April 1981 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - B (I), 1974-1978 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - B (II), 1958-1981 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - C (I), 1972-1980 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - C (II), 1978-1981 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - D, 1975-1981 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - E, 1973-1980 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - F, 1974-1980 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - G, 1974-1981 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - H, 1974-1980 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - I, 1976-1980 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - J, 1976-1980 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - K, 1974-1981 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Lein, Donald H., Tenure Review, February 1981 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - L, 1975-1982 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - M, 1975-1982 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - N (I), 1974-1979 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - N (II), 1978-1982 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - N (III), 1971-182 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - O, 1975-1981 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - P, 1974-1981 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Q, 1976-1981 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - R, 1974-1981 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - S (I), 1971-1982 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - S (II), 1974-1979 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - S (III), 1974-1982 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - T, 1971-1981 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - U, 1979-1981 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - V, 1974-1981 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - W, 1974-1981 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - X, Y, Z, 1974-1980 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - A (I), 1979-1986 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - A (II), 1981-1986 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - B (I), 1982-1986 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - B (II), 1976-1982 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - B (III), 1977-1986 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - C (I), 1973-1986 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - C (II), 1978-1986 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - C (III), 1982-1985 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - D, 1975-1986 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - E, 1981-1985 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - F, 1978-1986 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - G (I), 1976-1986 (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - G (II), 1978-1984 (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - H (I), 1980-1986 (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - H (II), 1980-1986 (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - J, 1975-1986 (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - K, 1976-1986 (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - L, 1980-1986 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - M(I), 1980-1986 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - M(II), 1977-1986 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - N, 1974-1986 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - O, 1977-1986 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - P, 1973-1986 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Q, 1963-1986 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - R (I), 1982-1986 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - R (II), 1976-1982 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - S (I), 1981-1985 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - S (II), 1983-1986 (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - S (III), 1976-1983 (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - T (I), 1978-1986 (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - T (II), 1977-1986 (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - U, 1976-1983 (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - W, 1976-1986 (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - Weide, 1978-1984 (Box 10, Folder 17)
  - X, Y, Z, 1976-1985 (Box 10, Folder 18)
  - A, 1979-1986 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - BA-, 1986-1988 (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - BL-, 1986-1987 (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - C, 1986-1987 (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - D, 1984-1987 (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - DeRosa, Morella, 1983-1987 (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - E, 1986-1988 (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - F, 1986-1987 (Box 12, Folder 13)
  - G (I), 1986-1988 (Box 12, Folder 15)
  - G (II), 1986-1987 (Box 12, Folder 16)
  - G (III), 1977-1986 (Box 12, Folder 17)
  - HA, 1985-1987 (Box 12, Folder 18)
  - HI, 1982-1988 (Box 12, Folder 19)
  - Hyde, Jack, 1982-1987 (Box 12, Folder 20)
  - J, 1986-1987 (Box 12, Folder 21)
  - K, 1984-1988 (Box 12, Folder 22)
  - L, 1986-1987 (Box 12, Folder 23)
  - MA-, 1983-1987 (Box 12, Folder 24)
  - MI-, 1986-1987 (Box 12, Folder 25)
  - N, 1987 (Box 12, Folder 26)
  - O, 1986-1987 (Box 12, Folder 27)
  - P, 1984-1987 (Box 12, Folder 28)
  - Q, 1987 (Box 12, Folder 29)
  - R, 1985-1987 (Box 12, Folder 30)
  - S, 1977-1988 (Box 12, Folder 31)
  - T, 1982-1986 (Box 12, Folder 32)
  - W, 1986-1987 (Box 12, Folder 33)
  - XYZ, 1985-1987 (Box 12, Folder 34)
- Series III. College of Veterinary Medicine, Mississippi State University
  - Research Project Evaluation, 1982, November 1982 - January 1983 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Research Review, January 18-21, 1981, January 1981 - March 1981 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Research Advisory Committee, October 1982 - November 1982 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Comprehensive Examination Reports, 1978-1980 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - External Examiners, May 1985 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Comprehensive Exam, May 1984, April 1984 - June 1984 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Phase II Exam, May 1-5, 1983, February 1983 - May 1983 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - 1983 Phase Ii Exam info, miscellaneous memos, May 1983 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence, March 1982 - September 1982 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - End of Phase II Examinations, April 1982 - June 1982 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Report of External Examiners; Phase II. Classes of 1983 and 1984, May 1984 - June 1984 (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Miscellaneous Information, May 1985 (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Osburn, Bennie I., April 1982 - May 1982 (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Jones, E. Wynn, March 1979 - April 1985 (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - Troutt, H. Fred, June 1982 (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - Hidalgo, Richard J., November 1980 - April 1983 (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - Creech, Roy G., July 1980 - December 1981 (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - Welser, John E., November 1978 - March 1982 (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - Coulter, Dwight B., January 1979 - March 1982 (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence, January 1981 - September 1985 (Box 6, Folder 28)
  - Mid-Phase Exam, Mississippi State University, June 1981 (Box 6, Folder 29)
  - External Examination, Mid Phase I - December 1980, October 1980 - January 1981 (Box 6, Folder 30)
  - External Examination, End of Phase I - June 1980, March 1980 - July 1980 (Box 6, Folder 31)
  - End of Phase I Comprehensive Exams, Class of 1984, June 22-26, 1981+, May 1981 - June 1981 (Box 6, Folder 32)
  - External Examination End-of-Phase - June 1979, June 1979 - July 1979 (Box 6, Folder 33)
  - External Examination, Mid Phase I, December 1979, September 1979 - January 1980 (Box 6, Folder 34)
  - External Examination, December 1978, August 1978 - February 1979 (Box 6, Folder 35)
  - Research Review, January 18-21, 1981, 1980-1981 (Box 6, Folder 36)
  - Tenure Concepts, October 1980 - November 1980 (Box 6, Folder 37)
  - Miscellaneous Information, November 1981 - January 1983 (Box 6, Folder 38)
- Series IV. Travel Reports
  - Acha, Pedro; 8-9 December ,1982, August 1982 - December 1982 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Wetterberg, 30 November, 1982, November 1982 - January 1983 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - USAHA Annual Meeting, Nashville, 7-12 November 1982, February 1982 - November 1982 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Mississippi Research Advisory Committee Meeting, 14-17 November 1982, April 1982 - November 1982 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - BARD, Washington DC, 12-15 October 1982, September 1982 - November 1982 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Seminar for Teachers on Foreign Animal Diseases, Washington DC, 30 August - 3 September 1982, August 1982 - September 1982 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - American Society for Virology, 2-5 August 1982, April 1982 - August 1982 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - AVMA; Salt Lake City, 18-22 July 1982, February 1982 - August 1982 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - ARS-APHIS; Washington DC, 28-29 June 1982, May 1982 - June 1982 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - WHO Evaluation, UNDP Technician Training, Caribbean, 17-30 May 1982, May 1982 - December 1982 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Briefing for Caribbean, New York City, 11 May 1982, April 1982 - July 1982 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Mississippi Research Review and Phase II, 2-7 may 1982, February 1982 - May 1982 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Wetterberg, 19-20 April 1982, February 1982 - July 1982 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - IICA, Panama, 13-16 April 1982, March 1982 - May 1982 (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Dr. Nira Retig and Mrs. Leah Levine (BARD), 28-30 March 1982, March 1982 (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - TAC, BARD, Beltsville MA, 23-24 March 1982, February 1982 - May 1982 (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - APHIS, ARS, Washington DC, 2-3 March 1982, February 1982 - March 1982 (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - IICA, Washington DC, 2-5 February 1982, January 1982 - February 1982 (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - Trinidad, 23-30 January 1982, December 1981 - February 1982 (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - Biotechnology general, new York City, 16-18 January 1982, January 1982 - May 1982 (Box 8, Folder 20)
  - Mississippi Mid-Phase Exam, 13-19 December 1981, November 1981 - December 1981 (Box 8, Folder 21)
  - Regarding Trinidad, Miami, November 1981, April 1982 - February 1983 (Box 8, Folder 22)
  - IICA, Washington DC, 15-19 November 1981, November 1981 (Box 8, Folder 23)
  - USAHA Meeting, St Louis 10-16 October 1981, August 1981 - October 1981 (Box 8, Folder 24)
  - NREC Meeting, Syracuse, 16-18 September 1981, September 1981 (Box 8, Folder 25)
  - Morbidity and Mortality, Washington DC, 3-5 August 1981, July 1981 - August 1981 (Box 8, Folder 26)
  - American Veterinary Medical Association (AVMA), St. Louis, 20-23 July 1981, May 1981 (Box 8, Folder 27)
  - 9th Panamerican Congress on Veterinary Medicine and Animal Husbandry, Caracas, 26-31 July 1981, September 1980 - January 1981 (Box 8, Folder 28)
  - Wetterberg Foundation Meeting, 29 June 1981, June 1981 (Box 8, Folder 29)
  - BARD Meeting San Francisco, 9-15 May 1981, March 1981 - April 1981 (Box 8, Folder 30)
  - Gainesville, 20 February - 3 March 1981, January - February 1981 (Box 8, Folder 31)
  - TAC (BARD) Meeting, Beltsville MD, 1-3 February 1981, January 1981 - February 1981 (Box 8, Folder 32)
  - Northeast Regional Council (USDA), Arlington VA, 14 January 1981, October 1980 - January 1981 (Box 8, Folder 33)
  - Mid-Phase I Comprehensive Exams, Class of 1984, Mississippi State University, 13-18 December 1980, September 1980 - March 1981 (Box 8, Folder 34)
  - Pre-examination Meeting, Columbus MS, 29-31 October 1980, October 1980 (Box 8, Folder 35)
  - ASTMH (ACAV) Meeting, Atlanta, 6 November 1980, September 1980 - November 1980 (Box 8, Folder 36)
  - NYS Veterinary Medical Society 89th Annual Meeting, Weschester NY, 2-5 October 1980, July 1980 - October 1980 (Box 8, Folder 37)
  - USAHA, Louisville KY, 31 October - 5 November 1980, June 1980 - September 1980 (Box 8, Folder 38)
  - USDA Advisory to the Joint Council on Food and Agriculture, NRC, Beltsville MD, 22-26 January 1980, January 1980 - February 1980 (Box 8, Folder 39)
  - AVMA, Council on Biologic and Therapeutic Agents, Chicago, 8-10 October 1980, May 1980 - September 1980 (Box 8, Folder 40)
  - AVMA Meeting, Washington DC, 21-24 July 1980, May 1980 - July 1980 (Box 8, Folder 41)
- Series V. Material for friends and family, authored/collected by Poppensiek
  These spiral bound writings were an ongoing effort by Dr. Poppensiek to continue to educate and inform youth and adults alike. The topics are mainly science related and were inspired by his own ideas of knowledge that he thought was important or by subjects and concepts that were relevant to what people close to him were currently learning about in school. While each item is themed they often cover a wide range of topics within a single volume. They contain many color graphics and photos and some contain cover letters placed inside.
  - Musings about Avian Vocalizations and some Related Meanderings, n.d. (Box 13)
  - Some Elusive Observations about Speech (an addendum to the monograph about the uvula), n.d. (Box 13)
  - Behavioral Implications in the Life Style of a Nematomorph Parasite, n.d. (Box 13)
  - Saved from Mothballing, n.d. (Box 13)
    The Transformation United States Navy Amphibious Assault Ship LSM 286 to the Sea-Going Freight Vessel Gayhead
  - Hyenas, Kin to Viverrids?, n.d. (Box 13)
  - A Camel, a Bedouin Girl Shepherdess, and a Camel Spider (a solfugid arachnid, but not a spider), n.d. (Box 13)
  - Meandering (among Feisty Hummingbirds) in Biological Etymology, n.d. (Box 13)
  - Some Distinguishing Features of the Big Cats, n.d. (Box 13)
  - All Great Discoveries Begin as Simple Observations, n.d. (Box 13)
  - In Remembrance of a Beloved Cherokee, n.d. (Box 13)
    Information about Will Rogers
  - Bezoars and a taste of Persimmons, n.d. (Box 13)
  - Fruit-Eating Bats ("Flying Foxes") and Several Emerging Viruses that They Carry and Shed, n.d. (Box 13)
    (also including a rhetorical embellishment with a couple of harmless insectivorous bats)!
  - Cobalt and Kobald Sprites, n.d. (Box 13)
  - Meandering (Among Wildcats) in Biological Etymology, April 2006 (Box 13)
  - Biochromes; Pigments in Living Things.(A Glimpse Inside a Seed)!, July 2006 (Box 13)
  - Meandering (among some Viruses and Insect Vectors) in Biological Etymology, with a Tribute to the Excellence of a Peer-reviewed Professional Journal: "Emerging Infectious Diseases", Volume 12, Number 8, August 2006, and its Managing Senior Editor, Polyxeni Potter, September 2006 (Box 13)
  - Implications of Behavioral Control by Parasites, June 2007 (Box 13)
  - The Hepatitis Virus: Nuances of Its Diabolic Biochemical Pathogenicity, October 2008 (Box 13)
  - Sound Waves, Hair Cells, Mosquitoes and Viruses, 2009 (Box 13)
  - Limerick and Limericks, March 2009 (Box 13)
  - The Aromatic Violet Gland in the Tail of a Fox: A Supracaudal Scent Gland, June 2009 (Box 13)
  - Bacteriophages (Bacterial Viruses) Attack Bacteria (and sometimes convert harmless microbes into pathogens)!, June 2009 (Box 13)
  - Ancient Greek Philosophy (Attitude, Curiosity, and Discipline) and The Birth of the Biomedical Sciences, July 2009 (Box 13)
  - Yawning and Its' Influence on Physiognomy in Art, July 2009 (Box 13)
  - Lot, Amun, Ammon, Moab, and Amen(One Observation Leads to Another)!, September 2009 (Box 13)
  - Some Meanderings in the Labyrinth of History!, October 2009 (Box 13)
    (All Because Josephine, Wife of Napoleon, had a Pet Pug)
  - Some Observations about the Cuttlefish, October 2009 (Box 13)
    The Chameleon of the Sea!
  - An Epiphany about (and an Apology to) the Uvula, November 2009 (Box 13)
  - The Tale of a Remarkable Green Sea Slug and equally Remarkable Red-tipped Giant Marine Tube-Worm>, February 2010 (Box 13)
  - Peering into the Labyrinths of Flea and Tapeworm Biology, April 2010 (Box 13)
  - Some Visions of the Invisible: A Flashing Glimpse into the Souls of William Edward Burghard DuBois, Alexander Crummell, Auguste Rodin, and George Grey Barnard, May 2010 (Box 13)
  - “If Stones Could Speak….. What Tales They might Tell", especially dolmens, menhirs, cairns and henges!, July 2010 (Box 13)
  - Hybrids and Chimeras and along the edges!, September 2010 (Box 13)
  - Free Radicals (Super Oxides), Proanthocyanodins, Apoptosis, and Michondrions! Aging!, November 2010 (Box 13)
  - Vignettes of a Visit to Moscow, By a People-to-People Mission of American Veterinarians early during the decade of the 1960’s, December 2010 (Box 13)
  - Borrequita y el Taimado.. pero Bobo.. Coyote! (Borrequita and the Crafty.. but Foolish.. Coyote!), January 2011 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Naming the Days of the Week (with wandering tales for boiler-plating), February 2011 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Some Moldy Sweet Clover, Some Dicumarol and Some Slippery Bolshevic Intrigue, March 2011 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Ambling through the Names of the Months while prodding like a quidnune will disclose that "He or She who Pryeth into Every Tacked-on Cloud of Secrecy May be Struck Like a Thunderbolt", April 2011 (Box 14, Folder 4)
    -includes supplement
  - All This And Braunschweiger Too! (Liver Sausage with Bacon) Smoked., September 2011 (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - They Quipped, Saying that my Rhapsodic Petrology Professor "has Rocks in His Head"! Now Those Rocks are in My Head!, ca. October 2011 (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - A Moment in a Spotlight for Basalt (a Supplement to the Monograph on Rocks and Rock Minerals), October 2011 (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - A Saga of Two Asian Water-Chestnut Plants, a Snail, and the Giant Intestinal Fluke Fasciolopsis buski, December 2011 (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Christmas in Poland, December 2011 (Box 14, Folder 9)
    (with two Polish Veterinarians and their families)
  - Tale Wagging Among Three Old Fossils, December 2011 (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - A Journey through Labyrinths of Parasitology, with focus (and many digressions) on the ubiquitous Lancet liver fluke Duicrocoelium dendriticum!, February 2012 (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - Look at What the Beagle Brought Home!, March 2012 (Box 14, Folder 12)
    Charles Darwin information
  - Peering Into the Life of a Brachiopod, March 12, 2012 (Box 14, Folder 13)
    (a marine bivalve that flourished 400 million years ago)!
  - Plutonic Intrusive Igneous Rock or Pluto, Persephone, and Six Pomegranate Arils (with seeds), April 2012 (Box 14, Folder 14)
  - The Lingering Effects of Greek and Roman Mythology on the Biomedical Language; Notably in Anatomy and Physiology, July 2012 (Box 14, Folder 15)
  - Buffalo and Bison and Buffalo Milk Cheese, November 2012 (Box 14, Folder 16)
  - Cheese from Sheep Milk and a couple of referees to milk from (water) buffalo., n.d. (Box 14, Folder 17)
  - The Most Popular Breeds of Dairy Cattle in the United States, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 18)
  - The Last Chapter Hasn't Been Written!, October 2012 (Box 14, Folder 19)
    Contains information about South Africa, Black African Heron, Kalaharai Plateau, Bushman, Bettles, Monarch Butterfly, Impala horn and more.
  - The Last chapter Hasn't Been Written! Monograph II, November 2012 (Box 14, Folder 20)
  - Dig Deeply, my Friend! (two stories behind two stories), December 2012 (Box 14, Folder 21)
    Information on Joseph Conrad, Samuel Taylor Coleridge, Rime of the Ancient Mariner, Albatross and more.
  - A Prelude and a Postlude to Endosymbiosis among Chloroplasts of Plant Cells and Mitochondria of Plant and Animal Cells, January 2013 (Box 14, Folder 22)
  - Misconceptions about Anatomical Structure or Function, The Pineal Gland, January 2013 (Box 14, Folder 23)
  - Emerging Infectious Diseases, Vector-borne Infections, February 2013 (Box 14, Folder 24)
  - Tales (even with some Tails) Behind Transmissible Spongiform Encephalopathy, February 2013 (Box 14, Folder 25)
  - Life, as we know it, Began in a Bacterium! The Ancient Sophisticated Bacterium: Cyanobacterium!, April 2013 (Box 14, Folder 26)
  - From Vomer to Vomeronasal Gland to Pheromones, June 2013 (Box 14, Folder 27)
  - Etymological Nuances of Primate Hands. Bonobos, Chimpanzees, and Pygmies., August 2013 (Box 14, Folder 28)
  - Musings about Fruit Seeds and Restraint in Overwhelming Population Growth Among, Bonobos, vis-a-vis Chimpanzees., August 2013 (Box 14, Folder 29)
  - Fruits, Seeds, and Fables III, October 2013 (Box 14, Folder 30)
  - Gypsies, Gypsy Violins, and Gypsy Music, October 2013 (Box 14, Folder 31)
    With special tribute to a very old Bohemian violin that is still willing to play it's heart out.
  - What's in a Name? (an etymologist's garden patch)!, January 2014 (Box 14, Folder 32)
    Polyphemus asked his captive Odysseus: What's your name? Odysseus replied: My Name is Nobody!
  - Five Odd Cousins (all are polyphyodonts), April 2014 (Box 14, Folder 33)
    with some Background Vistas for Arousing Curiosity! (Dr. Poppensiek indicates on the cover that this may be his last monograph)
  - Some Ancient Beliefs in Biological Names (Mostly Anatomical Names Still in Use) except epistropheus!, June 2014 (Box 14, Folder 34)
  - A Journey Through the Wilderness of Biomedical Etymology (with remnants of history along the way), September 2014 (Box 14, Folder 35)
  - Hands, October 2014 (Box 14, Folder 36)
    Hands that Paint. Hands that Suffer. Hands that Heal. And that which is behind the hands!
  - Roamin' in the Rumen I and II, February 2015 (Box 14, Folder 37)
    Transforming Volatile Fatty Acides into ATP, and wrapping DNA around Histones: Silent Barnyard Pastimes among Ruminants who never grimace or complain!
  - Bread, April 2015 (Box 14, Folder 38)
    Dr. Poppensiek indicates this will probably be his last monograph
  - Wandering through the Labyrinths of Biomedical Science (and meeting some distinguished scholars there), June 2015 (Box 14, Folder 39)
    The Staging Area for this Monograph is in the Limbic System and Vesicles at the Base of the Brain.
  - The Lilliput Effect, July 2015 (Box 14, Folder 40)
- Series VI. Scrapbooks, Certificates and Plaques
  - Appointment as Dean, 1959 (Box 15)
  - Resignation; Dedication of Research Tower, 1973-1974 (Box 15)
    Scrapbook made by Mrs. Poppensiek
  - New Appointments (James Law Professor in Comparative Medicine), Awards, 1973-1985 (Box 15)
  - Retirement and Later Activities, 1988-1993 (Box 15)
  - Dedication of Area in Research Tower, 2000 (Box 15)
  - Speeches, Certificates, News clippings, Correspondence, 1950-1965 (Box 16, Folder 18)
  - Speeches, Certificates, Photographs, News clippings, Correspondence, 1936-2000 (Box 16, Folder 19)
  - Certificates and Early Work, 1937-1942 (Box 16)
  - High School Diploma, Bogota High School, 17 June 1936 (Box 18)
  - Annual Certificate of Registration: Registered Veterinarian, 1 July 1958 (Box 18)
  - Plaques, 1942-1966 (Box 18)
  - Plaques, 1960-1998 (Box 19)
  - Plaque, University of Pennsylvania, 1978 (Box 20)
  - Certificate: New York State Veterinary Medical Society, 1 January 1990 (Map-case DD-14, Folder 1)
- Series VII. Other Writings and Publications
  - Feasibility Study: College of Veterinary Medicine, University of Arizona, May 1972 (Box 17)
  - Research Tower (N. Y. S. College of Veterinary Medicine) Dedication, June 1974 (Box 17)
  - Bovine Health Research Center: Cause for Concern, Text by Nita Jager, 1977 (Box 17)
  - Studies on Foot and Mouth Disease, Report of the Argentine - United States Joint Commission on Foot and Mouth Disease (2 copies), 1966 (Box 17)
  - Aquatic Animal Health, 1973 (Box 17)
  - Historical Survey of Animal-Disease Morbidity and Mortality Reporting, 1966 (Box 17)